BRODY HILL

8055 Windrose Ave, Plano, TX 75024 972 743 3918 | <u>Email</u> | <u>LinkedIn | GitHub</u>

SUMMARY

During my time with Candidate Labs I observed a gap between data projects and business outcomes, highlighting the critical need to align data projects with concrete business goals. Conversations with leaders at Google and Microsoft further fueled my passion for ensuring data projects yield explainable and trustworthy results, particularly for non-technical stakeholders. I believe the principal value of a data professional lies not only in technical proficiency but in the skill to leverage tools like SQL, Python, Tableau, or Excel to drive meaningful change and generate insights that directly impact business success.

EDUCATION

Baylor University - Waco

Fall 2015 - May 2019

Bachelor of Business Administration - Deans List all four years.

Springboard - Data Science Fellow May 2023 - December 2023

Business Analytics Specialization Track

600+ active hour, 1000+ study hour program focused on the practical application of data analytics / science among real world business problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning: classification, regression, clustering, feature engineering Coding Languages and Top Skills: Python, Excel, Tableau, SQL, Power BI Python Packages and Skills: Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Pandas,

Numpy, Scipy

Analysis Skills: Data Wrangling, Data Visualization, Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data

Analysis, Data Modeling

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow (Business Analytics Specialization Track): Springboard May 2023 - Present

Completed 50+ mini-projects and three capstone projects, with an intense focus on practically applying data science and analytics to concrete and specific business objectives.

Met with Data Leaders across companies like JP Morgan, Accenture, Google, Microsoft, and Walmart to gain a relevant and practical view of how to apply my curriculum to specific business outcomes.

Selected Springboard Projects:

Understanding GPU Feature Importance Using Machine Learning - <u>Capstone Two</u>
Predicting Credit Card Fraud Using Machine Learning - <u>Capstone Three</u>
An Exercise In Data Storytelling and Visualization - See <u>Here</u>
Customer Segmentation Analysis – See <u>Here</u>
Using SQL to Gather Key Business Insights - See Here

Business Development: Verifiable Oct 2022 - March 2023

First BD hire focused on installing the verifiable platform within the healthcare payor space. Achieved 116% of my assigned quota before leaving to pursue Springboard.

Talent Manager: Candidate Labs May 2021 - Oct 2022 *Part of 75% reduction in workforce*

As the first talent team hire, I played a key role in building the responsibilities and the initial success of the function. Sourced, interviewed, and closed key roles (typically director through C level) for clients within the a16z, Sequoia Capital, Battery Ventures, and other tier-one VC firms' portfolios.

During my time with CL, I closed \$1.1M in search fees in one year and made Presidents Club
In the summer of 2022.

Senior Business Development Specialist: Gartner Jan 2020 - May 2021

Focused on installing the Gartner for the CFOs product within the State and Local Government Sector.

Exceed 100% of quota every month I was with Gartner. Through LinkedIn outreach, cold emailing, and cold calling, I sat and conducted meetings with CFOs within state and local government agencies across the West Coast territory.